<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ant&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ant&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flowering Moon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/flowering-moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/flowering-moon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Find me a planet with a flowering moon. A core so bright, a membrane so teeming with life that its excess leaks out into orbiting chunks of rock and forces them into the cosmic beauty contest. A world so pre-occupied with growing itself that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop to notice it has inspired some other transformation entirely. Oxygen on a moon - an atmosphere at all - would be quite a feat. What makes a moon a moon? Does its classification necessitate an arid, lifeless signature, or can it be allowed to develop a culture, so long as it continues to revolve around the giving entity? Can a moon break off and take its newfound knowledge further into the galaxy, or is it bound by gravitational matrimony?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering What I Forgot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/remembering-what-you-forgot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/remembering-what-you-forgot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t want to waste a chance at love. You spent your life architecting the future you thought you wanted, and you have brought much to fruition. However, in your quest to achieve maximum potency in all things you do, you stumbled into a realm that stripped away the layers of armor you&amp;rsquo;d mistaken for &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. While searching for latent genetic treasures, you accidentally tumbled the lock on what you knew at birth and forgot sometime after preschool. Love is the most valuable experience a human could acquire, not because it is some spiritual marvel or because it is the divine subject of some stellar entanglement, but because that is what our biology craves more than shelter or food alone. Love is the difference between humans and animals, and lifted us from evolutionary struggle amongst violent, terrifying, powerful beasts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Burned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-i-burned/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-i-burned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guilt is what I burned to finally embrace my role in living. For most of my life I felt like the catalyst in some chemical reaction gone wrong. I am a uniter, a mediator, the product of primal compromise. Guilt from my involvement in the destruction of two lives colored every experience I had, despite monumental effort on the part of my victims to conceal this fact. I craved recognition and refused to accept anything less than self-excellence, but shied away from attention out of certainty that I would disappoint or cause some deeply festering disdain to re-emerge within my audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I burned this creature that grew inside me when I was 22 years old in a fire of hallucinogenic bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ll Know When</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/youll-know-when/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/youll-know-when/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sweep the room, clear the dust, and wipe away everything old. Thoughts become stale and tend to hang around long after they are obsolete. It takes a deliberate act of hunting down the leftovers to realize that you are breathing in more than just the fresh air you&amp;rsquo;re going for. Check the cushions for loose change, you&amp;rsquo;ve surely dropped a gem here or there along the way. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to keep a spotless mind, you don&amp;rsquo;t need a sterile workspace. You need a home that responds to clutter with open arms and cleverly showcases its imperfections, as if they were subjects of envy. You need to treat that place like a garden or a forest, using and consuming the fruits and the wood, constantly tending to its health and happiness, and never overworking in the name of maximizing gain. Don&amp;rsquo;t spend your would-be restful hours panicked at the growing state of entropy; this is exactly how things should be. You&amp;rsquo;ll know when it&amp;rsquo;s time to sweep the room.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Update Mid-2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/career-update-mid2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/career-update-mid2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I graduated from California State University, Monterey Bay, I was recruited alongside my capstone project teammates to go work for Booz Allen Hamilton, one of the largest and oldest government contracting companies in America. I had known very few things about that company when I received a job offer: that it was massively financially successful, that Edward Snowden had been employed there in some capacity during his exfiltration of classified documents revealing the illegal &amp;amp; unconstitutional existence of a dragnet wiretapping program led by the NSA, and that if I were a government, I would never pay a company to do something that I felt was necessary to do myself. I decided that an opportunity to jumpstart my career with a reputable and serious firm was too good to let my beliefs about how the world &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; work get in the way. I decided to move across the country and let an experience that I hypothesized would anger and disappoint me unfold - to test the validity of adolescent angst against reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did excellent work at Booz Allen Hamilton. I was assigned the ugliest, most byzantine projects they could safely assign to new hires and I wrestled meaning from decade old enterprise Java code like an archaeologist dusting off ancient stone tablets, consulting with the ivory-tower-dwelling sages of stackoverflow (&lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.co/company/press/archive/openai-partnership&#34;&gt;rest in peace&lt;/a&gt;) to bolt on upgrades and earn the respect and admiration of more seasoned colleagues previously tasked with the same job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was right&lt;/strong&gt; about a lot of things, namely that every signal I was attuned to screamed &amp;ldquo;this is not the most effective allocation of government funds&amp;rdquo; at varied volume and pitch. Out of politeness, I won&amp;rsquo;t enumerate those signals here, but understand that when I left that job after 2 years against the desire of a company which wanted to retain me and was only incentivized to promote and reward me, I considered I now owed 2 years to an indisputably &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; cause as penance. It did not sit right with me that so much taxpayer money went straight to the contracting/management consulting industry - which is overwhelmingly comprised of and could be the encompassing description of - the military industrial complex which itself prioritizes money and weapons far higher than its own service members. I &lt;em&gt;believed&lt;/em&gt; this was wrong as a 14 year old reader and viewer of the Iraq war, witnessing far more than a child probably should thanks to the uncensored web of the early 2000s, I &lt;em&gt;believed&lt;/em&gt; it was wrong as a college student attempting to &amp;ldquo;just focus on the cool tech&amp;rdquo; while my university masterfully subdued and realigned me with numerous ethics courses, and now I finally &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; it in a way that none but the crankiest of grandfathers could hand-wave away as youthful naivete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was wrong&lt;/strong&gt; in some areas, too, mostly in thinking that these infamous spaces would be inhabited by outright crooks with evil goatees and sinister personalities. I found, nearly everywhere I looked, hardworking, family-oriented, regular people doing their best to make things right for the people they loved in a system they truly believed in. These were not overwhelmingly cishet white men, as I had expected. I saw what could be described as a sign that the dream of America as a cultural melting pot was not completely dead. The presence of black and brown workers felt comforting and familiar for a California transplant in Virginia. Overall, I realized that most people are good, but the cross-section of Americans who have the luxury of the time and education necessary to examine systems wholistically in order to determine righteousness is shamefully small, and even if they &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; have that, what does it matter if the only options that put food on the table are problematic?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In America, the only jobs that can sustain a family are overtly or covertly about enriching the rich.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*This is a generalization I wish to disprove, that saddens me deeply, but still feels right.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my head, it was a difficult and terrifying journey from &amp;ldquo;a guaranteed, set-for-life, early-retirement&amp;rdquo; quality of life - something that my parents had decidedly &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; seen and had worked incalculably hard to make possible for me - to anything more aligned with my frustratingly rigid personal ethics. I decided on moving back to my home state of California and to take the transition realistically, gradually. I would find another lucky opportunity in an income-lateral job working again as a contractor, this time on the personnel &amp;amp; healthcare side of the Dept. of Defense. It was entirely unsexy; for the first few months I had no desk and a broken chair procured from the Dank Closet of Abandoned Office Furniture, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the whole place was full of actively harmful mold. I worked with some wonderful, smart people during a period of near-total disarray - this was Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s DoD which felt at times like the inmates running the asylum - but ultimately was still not able to convince myself that it was the right fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At my first job, I had &lt;em&gt;a version of the best&lt;/em&gt; of business infrastructure and support necessary for software development to make an impact at scale, with no guiding moral mission that would ensure I was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebignewsletter.com/p/why-is-booz-allen-renting-us-back&#34;&gt;really helping those in need&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At my second job, I had great people with a clear desire and mission to help people who absolutely deserved our help, with little to no oversight or care from the places that absolutely should have cared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My third job could be it. The job to end all job searches. An environmental nonprofit with the mission of &lt;strong&gt;scalable carbon reduction&lt;/strong&gt;. Sure, there it is. Sign me up. Anything I can build to advance that mission, I&amp;rsquo;ll do it. Surely there is no shortage of software need in that space, and I build software and am willing to do it for a less-than-evil wage. It means I don&amp;rsquo;t have to waste my life building better ad-targeting systems while the biosphere crumbles. It means I could put back into the system what I got out of it, maybe even boost it an order of magnitude. It means I could maybe have kids someday and be able to look them in the eye and tell them I &lt;em&gt;tried&lt;/em&gt; to make it better and you can too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, though, the company has a comfortable, tangible path toward consistently reducing carbon emissions in a few states for at least a few years that doesn&amp;rsquo;t include &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; software engineering. Due to some things that I fully understand and some that I don&amp;rsquo;t, they&amp;rsquo;re in a position to choose a well-defined, sensible path at the cost of &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; talent and a force-multiplier on a gamble that &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; allow themselves to be positioned as a nationally-recognized environmental consulting firm. They&amp;rsquo;re at a pivot point: take a big risk, spend a lot more, insert themselves into an entirely new business, or retreat and keep doing the thing that is consistently bringing in money - which they use to help the community. While it is frustrating to be great at your job, to be right about things for 4 years and be largely ignored, then politely shown the door, I cannot in my heart of hearts fault anyone for choosing slower economic growth in 2024 America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be a huge personal loss for me to part ways with my team - a group of passionate, empathetic, ethical nerds with seemingly infinite patience - who has stubbornly and with great care attempted to contort ourselves into any shape palatable by the larger organization in furtherance of collective empowerment toward the stated mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will lose no sleep over no longer having to sit through the garish displays of toxic positivity which boils my blood due to its suffocating effect on honest communication and the pressure it creates to live in delusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it seems I&amp;rsquo;m at the next &lt;strong&gt;shattering point&lt;/strong&gt;, the point at which the topography of the flaws of the current belief system is revealed and made available for self-study, the point at which any responsible builder should ask themselves: &lt;em&gt;where should I build next&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like it to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be unimpeachably dedicated to a national priority (climate change, voting rights, affordable housing, saving the fucking bees idk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the shifting of American culture back toward empathy and safety (undoing decades of pervasive apathy and fearmongering by &amp;ldquo;conservatives&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide enough money so that I can buy a house and start a family&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Journalism?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/computational-journalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/computational-journalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Friday, June 7th, a warm summer evening as innocuous as any other. A tenuous calm waned in the mind of one computer programmer; he was approaching middle age in an era of, if you took the majority of published news media as a trustworthy source (and he did), abject and incalculable, omnipresent and impending catastrophe. From an early age he yearned to help; anyone and everyone and everything that called to him, often with little thought to the consequences of haphazard volunteering to correct the incorrect, to right wrongs that were much older and wiser than he. Yet, after nearly a decade of working in the real world, he couldn&amp;rsquo;t shake the feeling that his talents (if there were any) were often wasted - writing muscles left to atrophy when the corporation demanded pixel-pushing, creativity made to starve because &amp;ldquo;we don&amp;rsquo;t want better, we want good enough now™ &amp;ldquo;, and a growing sense that generally, the interests of people who employ software engineers were often diametrically opposed to his own. Where he wanted impact, they wanted revenue. Where he wanted education, they wanted mindshare. And most of all, where he wanted a collaborative exchange of the beauty bestowed upon each individual member of society, he found a transactional paradigm in which only the shrewdest players advanced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everywhere he looked, he saw chaos. The world at once, seemingly without warning, was experiencing itself in full magnitude from every angle at once, a phenomenon he recognized from his own adolescence, though it appeared to be going much worse for the world. If the medium is the message, what is the lesson we are all imbibing with our mass addiction to hypermedia?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These thoughts were typical of our anxious protagonist on any given day at any given time, making a friendly chat about nothing at all quite elusive, a fact that annoyed many of his friends some of the time and himself all of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, something interjected this time - a nugget of gold glimmering brightly in the otherwise destitute mines of social media doomscrolling. A job posting? At ProPublica. Hmm. Surely this was just another false hope delivered with carelessness by the greatest purveyor of false hope in a decade: LinkedIn. After all, it had delivered no less than 100 fake opportunities earlier that week alone. While his ego was distracted, gummed up by the ruminative trap of &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t get your hopes up&amp;rdquo;, he quietly consented with a runaway thumb to please learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A computational journalist? What&amp;rsquo;s that? A lie. He knew what that was - or rather - what that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be. Certainly, there should be plenty more of those than he could account for currently in the news. Sure, there are those New York Times data-geeks that like to quantify everything conceivable, to plop a huge chunk of javascript and fancy graphs that no one is going to fumble around with in the 17th story about Donald Trump they skimmed that week. That approach, the &amp;ldquo;give them data and they will come&amp;rdquo; crowd who seem to think of data as an end in itself rather than a means to telling a compelling story, had always felt exclusionary and shortsighted to him. After all, he knew the composition of those magical little boxes embedded in the text: it was all just a hunk of likely unreproducible and poorly maintained javascript wrapped five times over in other layers of equally dubious javascript. The computational experiences dreamt up by siloed writers or scientists &lt;em&gt;who dabble&lt;/em&gt; always seemed to lack the illustrative and captivating qualities of staring at good painting or getting lost in a song you just heard for the first time. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t their fault, though - they were playing in a different arena with entirely different rules and could do lots that he couldn&amp;rsquo;t. He just happened to know of one enlightening bit of cosmic irony that gave him a relatively unique perspective, and, generously, an edge. Computer and information scientists of the last half-century worked tirelessly toward a future of &lt;em&gt;hypermedia&lt;/em&gt;, like traditional forms of media but with superpowers. They succeeded beyond belief, only to be robbed of the era they were trying desperately to usher in - the era of infinite canvas - a grand linking of all the disciplines across the globe in every way that could matter - by soulless sycophants whose desire for absolute power made this whole business of publishing on the web so complex it has been relegated to the dark arts - unless of course you are willing to shell out &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; a lot of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, computational journalism would be a good thing. We need more of those. He bargained with himself that since he doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any obvious portfolio of works that could fall under such a category, he was unlikely to be considered. That is, unless he was able to very rapidly put together some sort of something to show that he has potential. Just something very quick, less than say&amp;hellip; two 8 hour days&amp;hellip; something that could live inside an existing ProPublica article, that brought in data from external sources, and has an inherent usefulness as a supporting role in clarifying our complex world. Maybe that could work, he thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He tried to talk himself out of his favorite kind of endeavor (unstructured, fairly mentally arduous, and unlikely to succeed), but it just didn&amp;rsquo;t work. His last concern was something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;how would someone even communicate that sort of thing&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protein</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/protein/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/protein/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While poking around the web researching nootropics to add to the &amp;ldquo;loosely experiment with substances that make capitalism more tolerable&amp;rdquo;, I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://examine.com&#34;&gt;examine&lt;/a&gt;, a website whose headline reads: &amp;ldquo;Nutrition and supplement information you can trust&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m always skeptical of any website that does anything, because of how horribly uncreative people have ruined the web. This one seemed to contain a bunch of legitimate medical research / academic papers distilled into summaries and guides by real, actual humans. Sorta like if &lt;a href=&#34;https://erowid.org&#34;&gt;Erowid&lt;/a&gt; and webmd (eek!) had a baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it turns out, I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be consuming 110+ grams of protein every day, assuming normal (minimal) levels of physical activity. I never knew that. I typically ate ~30g of protein a day for &amp;hellip;the entire duration of my life aside from a short period of intense exercise during which I felt it was &lt;em&gt;obvious&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;necessary&lt;/em&gt; to gulp down protein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been about 10 days and I feel &lt;em&gt;much, much better&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks protein.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enwebbed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/enwebbed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/enwebbed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe that the web survives because of this strange phenomenon where you can see one of my thoughts and become my friend for 45 seconds. You. Wherever you are in relation to me temporally, culturally, financially; regardless of my status, my job title, my choice of clothing or even my general temperament. You don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about me, save for this one thought that crawled out of the perplexagonal grunt machine that rests behind my eyes. I become defined entirely by a single interaction I had with a machine, in isolation, and you, upon discovery of a mental doppleganger or refreshingly untrodden territory, become a member of a tribe which may not yet exist.  With explicit consent and unbelievable ease, our connection could be as short as a moment and as deep as the emotional core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a decade, this was our collective hallucination: open, distributed, and inclusive world-building. The internet exploded into consciousness and &lt;em&gt;demanded&lt;/em&gt; we spin a web together! Technology developed under the guise of machinery of war went moonlighting as a means for liberation. I caught a glimpse of this event - tilting and clicking on the beige box in my grandparents&amp;rsquo; garage before I could fully read. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know what I was seeing and took it all for granted until much later, now that the deterioration of the magic is psychologically destabilizing. The web used to strategically link us together on-demand for great moments in a sort of infinite show-and-tell. Not anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, people are tied together in knots by a cabal of addiction-peddling supervillains. You are not allowed to forget your high school crush; You must remain connected to your middle school bully; their marriage to each other is required viewing on your timeline. Every true moment of human interaction in your life is now an exploitable trigger point for the grand capitalist&amp;rsquo;s sale of | Sustainable | Free Range | Micromodal | Couples&amp;rsquo; Matching Underwear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of your connections are superficial. Sorry, we don&amp;rsquo;t support collaboration or nuanced concern, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to choose one of the five Emotion Badges handcrafted by our world-class Emotioneers . Not expressive enough? You can pull a gif from the Unified Historitainment Stream! As long as it&amp;rsquo;s not too taboo, deemed too critical of class or poverty, or infringes upon the beliefs of any nation we seek to do business with now or at any point in the future! Oh, and the first 5 rows are paid ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss the old web when people &lt;em&gt;paid&lt;/em&gt; attention - always their own - a home where I was never algorithimically assigned a fraction of my peers&amp;rsquo; zombified lifeforce based on innumerable, unknowable transactions stamped across 12 availability zones faster than I can blink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, link me your blog. No, I won&amp;rsquo;t join threads.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hermits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hermit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 22:41:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hermit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The hermit is a beautiful bastard of a creature. Each hermit was once a vibrant, loving communitarian, known amongst their peers for superior intellect and fervent pursuit of knowledge. When the hermit is challenged, it toils away in isolation, stretching, lifting, pulling, rotating their mind in every which way as if to physically mimic the shape of the answer they seek. For the hermit, no solution is without a perceptible angle, it is simply a matter of finding the right squint. Many years of this skill building will lead the hermit into a dank and dusty lifestyle populated mostly by unfinished books, both read and written. If a hermit is lucky, they will cross paths with a witch, and become enchanted by a puzzle which does not appear to contain any problems at all. At this point, the hermit is stumped, but will refuse to let old habits die and instead spend a lifetime of mental cycles attempting to re-orient its observatory organs in order to properly size up the subject of mystery. What a beautiful problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Moves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-moves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 13:32:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-moves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I look at a fretboard, I am aware that I am seeing something beyond the wood. I know that somewhere within, every song I will ever and &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; ever stumble into writing is lying dormant, cut into shy, inconspicuous fragments and scattered across six strings. I know it is the task and pleasure of my life to dig out the secrets which, while locked away in the corpse of a tree I have never met, are undeniably my own. I know these secrets do not live in me; they are transfused through the gentle kissing of rosewood and fingertips, and expose the things I seek to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder what a dancer sees when she looks upon herself. Does her body serve as the
conduit for that same uncanny void, or is each routine cultivated in a garden of self-discovery with care and intentionality? Is elegance in movement an inseparable product of the feet and the ground they touch? Could I learn to move myself like an instrument in the same way I’ve learned to move sound?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public University or Corporate Intellect Farm?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/public-university-or-corporate-intellect-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 20:52:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/public-university-or-corporate-intellect-farm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Any system of university exists to create an informed and capable public, not, as
some neoconservative think-tanks might have you believe, as simply a
mechanism for employment in service of the Great Economic Machine.
What does it say about a culture when its brightest minds are busy
tinkering away in colorful, infantilized office playgrounds, aimed
narrowly at constructing marvelous contraptions for social addiction?
In 2020, a year of century-defining global pandemic, does the world
need more virtual mustaches, flirtatious extremism, and incessant
interruption? That there exist corporations valued in the trillions
headquartered in the same space where millions go hungry,
relegated to sleeping on the street? I believe it says that only a
privileged few ever really get a glimpse of the whole picture; only
those who are sufficiently free from financial panic are granted the
express freedom of true engagement with the perspective induced by
academia. If every member of a society were to peer into the
looking-glass, many would outright renounce their roles in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then, are the blinders applied to those of extraordinary intellect? Simply, the
snake of industry has turned inward unto its own tail and inserted it
promptly into its mouth. Corporations too often form with innocuous
motives, acquire skilled members, find small success, and at this
point rather than attempt to sustain that success, make morally
dubious trade-offs in search of ever-greater success, repeating this
vicious cycle until someone spots an inevitable systemic failure and
escapes the sinking ship with armfuls of riches, leaving the rest of
the crew to drown. Before that cataclysm, as the spiral grows, the
enticement of the skilled laborer becomes more fiendish - salary,
stock options and meeting-rooms stocked with beer and games, all
serving the purpose of distracting a potential employee from their
societal responsibility to return the knowledge bestowed upon them by
the public school system to their peers! So efficient has this
university-to-tech-industry pipeline become, we barely perceive the
impropriety. You might feel it when you pass by the homeless and are
faced with the juxtaposition that you and they are one in the same,
yet you have a home and they have nothing, and you are primed
with no social response to this dilemma. Silicon Valley, San
Francisco, New York, insert tech hub here - all generating
lighting-fast networks of unprecedented technical marvel and massive
wealth alongside them. How can cities that scrape the sky be
so unwilling to provide for their boots on the ground? Where are all
the whiz-kids of pop-culture lore in the face of these problems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this the purpose of higher education? Do we mean to siphon resources from public
domain to public nuisance? Can Big Tech quantifiably prove that the
unprecedented level of connection they provide enables a net-positive
for our social psyche? In the past three decades, we have all but
delegated the responsibility of these interrogations to the industry
which itself seeks to profit from not responding. When we ask the
Mark Zuckerbergs of the world if they can distinguish between
poisoning the well and providing clean water, we are left on read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime in the last decade, while most of us were busy watching cat videos, the invisible
tubes that bring us information were hijacked by a handful of
profit-driven corporations. Unlike the prior owners of these tubes,
these companies have no interest in providing a standardized, neutral
“platform” by which anyone can “link” to and from disparate
information publishers - a model which drives traffic away from the
provider themself, thus earning no money. Instead, they seek to lure
their users into pits of despair by prostituting journalism into the
lowest common denominator of fear and disgust, serving up content
deliberately calculated to cause anxiety, and dangling in front of us
the shiny objects of desire, machine-curated with the compute power
of entire nations for each and every one of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this - ALL of it - done without our express permission, and always to our
individual and collective detriment. What happened here? It is of
twisted irony that the incarceration capital of the world and
birthplace of the most expedient information delivery network in
history are one in the same. With one hand, we hastily confine
millions of our own citizens for inhaling the smoke of naturally
occurring flora, and in the name of freedom, we use the other to
justify the unchecked propagation of conspiracy theories which
actively jeopardize public safety. When “entrepreneurs” used
racial minorities as slaves to build the great American railways to
accumulate the wealth of small kingdoms and ensure their continued
domination, albeit late, eventually a governing body stepped
forward to reign in this atrocious abuse of power. If, beneath the
festering pile of corporate lobbyists, the United States government
retains any vestige of democracy, it will show itself now in reigning
in the feudal lords of our darling web. If, after decades of
capitalist conditioning, we citizens retain some semblance of
self-worth, we will demand reallocation of intellectual wealth away
from predatory data brokers and toward our collective well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiny Invisible Machines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tiny-invisible-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 20:39:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tiny-invisible-machines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At this exact moment on Earth, nature’s symphony is accompanied by the persistent hum of billions of tiny machines we have embedded into reality. These machines are dictated by the slightest variance in electrical impulses and power the world economy, yet only a small subset of us are privileged enough to ponder the implications of such invisible architecture. Fewer still have the magical combination of ability, power, and luck required to influence the design and implementation of these systems which will govern &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of our lives. That is why as software developers, we have an urgent responsibility to build &lt;em&gt;strictly and solely&lt;/em&gt; systems which respect the rights of its users, to educate our peers in other disciplines about the systems and their common pitfalls, and to demand public ownership of essential infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are likely not aware that the software you interact with is imbued with ulterior motives. How can a bunch of words and buttons on a screen &lt;em&gt;disrespect&lt;/em&gt; you? Thanks to the cunning legal teams behind major commercial software companies, the apps you run on your phone, tablet, and computer are allowed to perform egregious violations of your privacy while you watch your friends’ social broadcasts.  And in the United States, thanks to a defanged regulatory body and increasing oligarchic control of the legislature, the companies which siphon the most data about your personal habits grow the fastest - thus incentivizing &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; companies to adopt this strategy or die. The practice of collecting, processing, and analyzing users’ behavior to create digital shadows upon which advertising campaigns can modeled gives way to the absurdly high stock valuations which currently prop up our economy. By commodifying individuality, Big Tech has laid the groundwork for a marketplace of souls. How much are you worth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fsf.org/about/&#34;&gt;free software movement&lt;/a&gt; exists to provide shelter from these exploitative platforms. Free software bestows “four freedoms” onto its users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(freedom 0) the freedom to run the program as you wish, for any purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(freedom 1) the freedom to study how the program works, and change it so it does your computing as you wish. Access to the source code is a precondition for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(freedom 2) the freedom to redistribute copies so you can help your neighbor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(freedom 3) the freedom to distribute copies of your modified versions to others. By doing this you can give the whole community a chance to benefit from your changes. Access to the source code is a precondition for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When software is licensed according to these ideals, users can interrogate the electrons transporting their personal data, decide whether the functionality the software offers is worth the extraction, and sidestep the data → information → knowledge pipeline feeding into the surveillance software sludge factory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Web Rant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/open-web-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 13:30:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/open-web-rant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;image src=&#34;../images/spiderweb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;320&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-web-is-being-polluted-by-capital&#34;&gt;The Web is Being Polluted by Capital&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that the internet should be a freely available utility for all people. In its
purest form, the internet is the technology that enables the web - a portal through which
every global citizen can access the totality of human knowledge &lt;em&gt;for free&lt;/em&gt;. Insantaneous
free access to knowledge is the clearest facilitator of education we have witnessed since
the invention of the printing press, and should be embraced as a tool for
course-correcting centuries of global inequality deliberately inflicted by the
restriction of knowledge to elite groups. When corrupted by the financial allure of
centralization, the internet becomes a platform for exploitation and manipulation of the
least privileged members of society. My personal aspiration is to act in some way to
reverse the trend toward this reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stop-helping-them&#34;&gt;Stop Helping Them&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am greatly concerned about the consolidation of corporate control over the underlying
physical infrastructure and technical implementation that powers the web. As a software
developer, I am deeply troubled that many of my peers are forced by financial necessity
to work for organizations which are actively destroying the vision of the open web so
many of us share. For this reason, I have taken an ethical stance to remove myself from
the process of building a user-hostile web - I refuse to work for typical Silicon Valley
companies who place shareholder value over social responsibility; I will no longer build
infrastructure for any arm of the military industrial complex, nor will I assist in the
colonization of the web for the wealthy. I urge my peers who are in similar positions of
privilege to join me in this pledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We deserve to spend our engineering talent working
for organizations that create meaningful, accessible products &amp;amp; services  &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; cannibalizing the
society which enabled them to grow in the first place. The world will be a better place
when engineers are poised to solve the immediate crises of our time - climate
instability, discriminatory allocation of housing &amp;amp; food, and the hijacking of computer
networks to enable state-sponsored surveillance and propaganda. You are not responsible
for the circumstance you are born into, but you are the only one with the power to get
out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ieee-computer-society-code-of-ethics&#34;&gt;IEEE Computer Society Code of Ethics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.computer.org/education/code-of-ethics&#34;&gt;Code of Ethics&lt;/a&gt; from a prominent professional society
within one of the largest (and oldest) computing
organizations in the world - The IEEE (Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers) Computer
Society! The preamble begins below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computers have a central and growing role in commerce, industry, government, medicine, education, entertainment and society at large. Software engineers are those who contribute by direct participation or by teaching, to the analysis, specification, design, development, certification, maintenance and testing of software systems. Because of their roles in developing software systems, software engineers have significant opportunities to do good or cause harm, to enable others to do good or cause harm, or to influence others to do good or cause harm. To ensure, as much as possible, that their efforts will be used for good, software engineers must commit themselves to making software engineering a beneficial and respected profession. In accordance with that commitment, software engineers shall adhere to the following Code of Ethics and Professional Practice. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.computer.org/education/code-of-ethics&#34;&gt;IEEE CS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to highlight the inclusion of the line &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;To ensure&amp;hellip;that their efforts will be
used for good, software engineers must commit themselves to making software engineering a
beneficial and respected profession&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; as by now it has become clear to the average citizen that we
as an industry are quite far from this goal. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.propublica.org/article/facebook-advertising-discrimination-housing-race-sex-national-origin&#34;&gt;Facebook harvests your data to sell
hypertargeted ads - discrimination laws be damned&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21270290/youtube-deleting-comments-censorship-chinese-communist-party-ccp&#34;&gt;Google is courting China with political censorship&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.seattletimes.com/business/amazons-heavily-automated-hr-leaves-workers-in-sick-leave-limbo-amid-coronavirus-crisis/&#34;&gt;Amazon ignores the health and safety of its warehouse workers during a global pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.propublica.org/article/how-china-built-a-twitter-propaganda-machine-then-let-it-loose-on-coronavirus&#34;&gt;virtually every major social network is laden with state-sponsored propaganda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this because software engineers lean libertarian or simply have a laissez-faire attitude
toward technology&amp;rsquo;s impact on society? No. While I believe the responsibility lies with us
engineers, the Big Tech oligarchs (and their profit-driven boards) are at ultimately at
fault. The leader of an organization sets the tone for every member below them, and for
the entirety of my life, massive corporate giants have pushed knowledge workers to the
precipice of treason in the name of infinite growth, feeding their egos with mission
statements to &amp;ldquo;change the world&amp;rdquo;, disguising the chance to architect platforms of oppression as those of &lt;em&gt;expression&lt;/em&gt;, and numerous other forms of tactful misdirection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows this paragraph is a list of 8 principles that IEEE CS suggests embody the spirit of ethical software development. Critically, the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; responsbility we have is to the public interest!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ethics-code-iee-cs.png&#34; alt=&#34;Eight Principles - IEEE CS Code of Ethics&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PUBLIC – Software engineers shall act consistently with the public interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CLIENT AND EMPLOYER – Software engineers shall act in a manner that is in the best interests of their client and employer consistent with the public interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PRODUCT – Software engineers shall ensure that their products and related modifications meet the highest professional standards possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JUDGMENT – Software engineers shall maintain integrity and independence in their professional judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MANAGEMENT – Software engineering managers and leaders shall subscribe to and promote an ethical approach to the management of software development and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PROFESSION – Software engineers shall advance the integrity and reputation of the profession consistent with the public interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COLLEAGUES – Software engineers shall be fair to and supportive of their colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SELF – Software engineers shall participate in lifelong learning regarding the practice of their profession and shall promote an ethical approach to the practice of the profession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public interest is priority number one, above &lt;em&gt;employers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;product&lt;/em&gt; and even &lt;em&gt;self&lt;/em&gt;.
If you are a user of the proprietary platforms mentioned above, ask yourself whether
their leadership (Mark Zuckerberg, Jeff Bezos, Peter Thiel, etc) has &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; acted in the
public interest. If you can find an example, consider that good deed against the backdrop
of violations - in some cases the total subversion of democracy - and drop me a line at
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:anthony@symkowick.org&#34;&gt;anthony@symkowick.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code of Ethics: IEEE Computer Society. (n.d.). Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.computer.org/education/code-of-ethics&#34;&gt;https://www.computer.org/education/code-of-ethics&lt;/a&gt;
Copyright © 1999 by the Institute for Electrical and Electronics Engineers, Inc. and the Association for Computing Machinery, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day, M. (2020, June 5). Amazon&amp;rsquo;s heavily automated HR leaves workers in sick-leave limbo amid coronavirus crisis. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.seattletimes.com/business/amazons-heavily-automated-hr-leaves-workers-in-sick-leave-limbo-amid-coronavirus-crisis/&#34;&gt;https://www.seattletimes.com/business/amazons-heavily-automated-hr-leaves-workers-in-sick-leave-limbo-amid-coronavirus-crisis/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hern, A. (2017, June 19). Facebook and Twitter are being used to manipulate public opinion – report. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jun/19/social-media-proganda-manipulating-public-opinion-bots-accounts-facebook-twitter&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jun/19/social-media-proganda-manipulating-public-opinion-bots-accounts-facebook-twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kao, J., &amp;amp; Li, M. S. (n.d.). How China Built a Twitter Propaganda Machine Then Let It Loose on Coronavirus. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.propublica.org/article/how-china-built-a-twitter-propaganda-machine-then-let-it-loose-on-coronavirus&#34;&gt;https://www.propublica.org/article/how-china-built-a-twitter-propaganda-machine-then-let-it-loose-on-coronavirus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vincent, J. (2020, May 26). YouTube is deleting comments with two phrases that insult China&amp;rsquo;s Communist Party. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21270290/youtube-deleting-comments-censorship-chinese-communist-party-ccp&#34;&gt;https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21270290/youtube-deleting-comments-censorship-chinese-communist-party-ccp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile for Your Org</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/agile-for-your-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 17:04:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/agile-for-your-org/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-agile&#34;&gt;What is Agile?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile is a methodology for doing work - in my case that work is building Software. I&amp;rsquo;m
sure at this point, millions of words have been written about Agile development - most by
people much smarter and more credentialed than me! I encourage you to read some of the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://agilemanifesto.org/&#34;&gt;sacred texts&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you what works for
&lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-4-values&#34;&gt;The 4 Values&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individuals and interactions over processes and tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working software over comprehensive documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer collaboration over contract negotiation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responding to change over following a plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tl;dr be &lt;em&gt;proactive&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;open-minded&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;dedicated&lt;/em&gt; to a creative journey that may not
progress in a straight line!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a development standpoint, this is where I start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are we building?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are we building it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we do it without going insane?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few people who &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; software ever have to grapple with the philosophical ramifications
of codifying obscure incantations and etching them onto millions of devices. Most people
who &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; it understand perfectly well how coercing a machine into performing for humans
proves hazardous to the ego. So, we benefit in the long run by asking a lot of questions
up front. Not &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the questions - the client is a living, breathing, opinion-changing
beast, but just the bare necessities to give the idea corporeal form. This is called an
MVP - or Minimum Viable Product - and represents the absolute dinkiest version of the
product that can &lt;em&gt;still provide value&lt;/em&gt; to the users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-form-your-mvp&#34;&gt;How to Form Your MVP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to think of generating an MVP like a police sketch artist drawing from a witness&#39;
testimony. In an ideal world, you&amp;rsquo;d be able to just build the product from an exact set of
requirements. Unfortunately, we rarely get a complete &amp;amp; accurate picture from a single
source - a witness spots a tall man wearing a shirt - how many tall men wearing shirts
exist in the world? Likewise, clients may not have a clear or concise vision for the
product they need. It is your job (as a developer, product manager, or other agile
stakeholder) to help extract the vital functions of the would-be application and glue
them together in a pleasant, coherent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collect requirements in markdown format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create mockups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share mockups with client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collect feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TODO: create cycle diagram above&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things that facilitate your rapid iteration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Version Control System (git)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kanban (trello, jira)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaboration (slack, teams, jitsi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous Delivery/Integration (netlify, github, jenkins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KISS documentation (readme, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rust-lang.github.io/mdBook/&#34;&gt;mdbook&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsibility of Privilege</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/responsibility-of-privilege/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 18:44:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/responsibility-of-privilege/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this exact moment on Earth, nature&amp;rsquo;s symphony is accompanied by the persisten hum of
billions of tiny machines we have embedded into reality. These machines are dictated by
the slightest variance in electrical impulses and power the world economy, yet only a
small subset of us are privileged enough to ponder the implications fo such invisible
architecture. Fewer still have the magical combination of ability, power, and luck
required to actually influence the design and implementation of these systems which will
govern &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of our lives. That is why as software developers, we have an urgent
responsibility to build &lt;em&gt;strictly and solely&lt;/em&gt; systems which respect the rights of its
users, to educate our peers in other disciplines about the systems and their common
pitfalls, and to demand public ownership of essential infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;free-software-surveillance-state-oligarchy&#34;&gt;Free Software, Surveillance State, Oligarchy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;talk about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surveillance software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oligarchy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;software licensing
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;combines the former 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;neutralizes oligarchic power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education-digital-literacy-dark-patterns&#34;&gt;Education, Digital Literacy, Dark Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;municipal-fiber-internet-norway-commits-to-free-software-government-contracting&#34;&gt;Municipal Fiber Internet, Norway Commits to Free Software, Government Contracting&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Web Exposition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/small-web-exposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 11:27:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/small-web-exposition/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Your Terminal Spark Joy?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fancy-terminal-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 21:19:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fancy-terminal-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the list of development tools we have to choose from grows every day, the
humble unix terminal beckons us with simplicity and the promise of a
distraction-free experience. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve conquered the initial learning curve
of navigating a command-line interface, you may be craving some sugary features
you gave up ditching IDEs (Integrated Development Environments). Surely there
must be some middle ground between a lone blinking cursor and clunky GUIs
(Graphical User Interfaces)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read ahead for some helpful &lt;em&gt;reimagininings&lt;/em&gt; of classic Unix tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-man--tldr&#34;&gt;1. man &amp;amp; tldr&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I&amp;rsquo;d like to share the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tldr.sh/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tldr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; command, which provides a &amp;ldquo;just get me up
and running&amp;rdquo; familiarity with many unix commands. Inspired by the &lt;strong&gt;man&lt;/strong&gt;
command to read manual pages for a program, tldr is much more concise and shows
common one-line examples of how a program is used. Yes, you should still read
the man page, but this can save you some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compare the results below for Hugo, a static site generator:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ man hugo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/man-hugo.gif&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; height=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lots of info there&amp;hellip;could be a while!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ tldr hugo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;There we go! Immediately I know how the developer of hugo intends me to use it -
just type &lt;strong&gt;hugo new site&lt;/strong&gt; in any directory I&amp;rsquo;d like to create my website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/tldr-hugo.gif&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; height=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-cat---bat&#34;&gt;2. Cat -&amp;gt; Bat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man1/cat.1.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; command is pretty much
unavoidable when working with the terminal - it allows concatenation of files
(and printing them to standard output) and is the most common way to simply
spit out the contents of a file!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to see the contents of a JavaScript file, I would simply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cat example.js
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;and we would get the contents of the file, simply and without fanfare:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/cat.gif&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; height=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great, but the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sharkdp/bat&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; command improves
readability of code by adding line numbers and syntax highlighting, all without
sacrificing POSIX compatibility for piping into other programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ batcat example.js
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/bat.gif&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; height=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome! It even opens in a pager (like the &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; command) for vertical
scrolling. If you want this functionality by using the same keyword - cat - you
can set up an alias in your shell. I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zsh.org/&#34;&gt;zsh&lt;/a&gt;, and have
aliased bat as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;alias&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;cat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;batcat -n --color auto --style full&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-du---dust&#34;&gt;3. du -&amp;gt; dust&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;du&lt;/em&gt; command shows disk usage and can be used to determine which
directories are taking up the most space - useful when you&amp;rsquo;ve run out of said
space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ du
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/du.gif&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; height=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;er, ok, looks like we are listing folders and files with numbers prepended to
their entries. Hmm. You can see that it&amp;rsquo;s gonna take some grokking to make sense of this
data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s try the rust replacement, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bootandy/dust&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dust&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - like du but more intuitive, (straight from the
tool website)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ dust
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/dust.gif&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; height=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow, right away we are given a hierarchical view of the items within the
Downloads folder - accompanied by a graph of size by percentage - or how much of
the total folder size each subfolder is responsible for. Neat! Looks like that
recent free dump of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springer.com/us&#34;&gt;Springer Textbooks&lt;/a&gt; is taking
up 68%! Do I really need &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; those books??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dust is great for finding size of files, but how about our primary interface
for dealing with files and directories in the shell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-ls---exa&#34;&gt;3. ls -&amp;gt; exa&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ls is the simple &amp;ldquo;show me what you got&amp;rdquo; program to list all items in a
directory. It has some helpful options to enable showing hidden/dot files, file
sizes, permissions, and more. The below example will show off listing all
(including hidden) files in the &lt;strong&gt;-l&lt;/strong&gt; long format to get those other items I
mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ls -la --color
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ls.gif&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; height=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This looks all right, and &lt;strong&gt;ls&lt;/strong&gt; is pretty configurable as far as output formats.
However, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://the.exa.website/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;exa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; we get some enhanced color and
sane defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ exa -la
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/exa.gif&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; height=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See how the permissions and owners are also color-coordinated? Nice. The exa
website also notes that exa runs in parallel, so you might see much faster
performance working in huge directories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are just a few handy tools I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed to recently that I think
might help you. The year is 2020, and we can live in whatever time we want -
a splash of 1970 with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Swordfish90/cool-retro-term&#34;&gt;Cool Retro
Term&lt;/a&gt; mixed with powerful 2020
tools! If you enjoyed this post, please let me know, and if you have any
questions or noticed a mistake, feel free to reach out! If you read through
this blog post and thought, man, I&amp;rsquo;ve already known about these for years and I
breezed through this refresher, kudos to you, friend! But I&amp;rsquo;ve got something
for you too - check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nushell.sh/&#34;&gt;Nushell&lt;/a&gt;, it fits the theme
of this blog post but expands it to the whole shell itself. Nushell touts
composable tables as the primary method of interaction as opposed to totally
unstructured text.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Pollution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/data-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 15:33:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/data-pollution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-pollution---strain-on-the-cognitive-brain&#34;&gt;Data Pollution - Strain on the Cognitive Brain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;Medium&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Data Should We Share</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-data-should-we-share/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 15:25:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-data-should-we-share/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Is Cancelled, Thanks COVID-19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/work-is-cancelled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 10:56:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/work-is-cancelled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe title=&#34;In  the US, confirmed coronavirus cases double every 2nd to 3rd day. China, South Korea, Japan have already a flat curve.    &#34; aria-label=&#34;Interactive line chart&#34; id=&#34;datawrapper-chart-fjeZe&#34; src=&#34;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/fjeZe/1/&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;     style=&#34;background: white; padding: 25px; width: 0; min-width: 100% !important; border: none;&#34; height=&#34;675&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34;&gt;!function(){&#34;use stric    t&#34;;window.addEventListener(&#34;message&#34;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&#34;datawrapper-height&#34;])for(var e in a.data[&#34;datawrapper-height&#34;]){var     t=document.getElementById(&#34;datawrapper-chart-&#34;+e)||document.querySelector(&#34;iframe[src*=&#39;&#34;+e+&#34;&#39;]&#34;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&#34;datawrappe    r-height&#34;][e]+&#34;px&#34;)}})}();                                                                                                              
    24 &lt;/script&gt;
   
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flattenthecurve.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.flattenthecurve.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Compassionate Coders, Free Software Enthusiasts, &amp;amp; the Greater Millenial &lt;del&gt;Workforce&lt;/del&gt; Quarantine Squad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I completed my search. After just over 1 month and after many punishingly difficult (failed) coding tests, I found a great job with great pay and a great work environment. I was all set to move when COVID-19 infection rates began climbing in the United States. I reached out to the company proactively, wondering if all this talk of curve-flattening and government lockdown would postpone my start date or worse. It was worse. I got a call the next day from a panicked &amp;amp; genuinely concerned &amp;ldquo;Head of Talent Acquisition&amp;rdquo; informing me with brevity and certainty that my signed employment contract, along with its generous bonus, were now being rescinded - and the Security Engineer position I was being brought on for &lt;em&gt;cancelled&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow. A sludge of emotion rose up inside of me as I realized the implication of what was being said to me through the phone. The time and energy spent searching, applying, test-taking, more test-taking, interviewing for behavior, for techincal prowess, for culture-fit. Buying a suit - remembering how to physically get in the suit and pass as self-respecting adult. All for nothing. I asked some clarifying questions that didn&amp;rsquo;t really need to be asked - what? it&amp;rsquo;s cancelled altogether? What about a delay? Am I still going to be hired when this virus blows over? No, the company at this point could commit to nothing more that &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re sorry, your job is cancelled and we hope to talk with you in the future.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And who can blame them? I&amp;rsquo;d be lying if I said I had analyzed the company&amp;rsquo;s economic viability or the resiliency of their business (savings, daily operating costs, etc) - and the first people I would cut in times of financial ruin would be those I had the shortest relationships with. While I am incredibly disappointed by this success turned failure, I would like to think that because I was not hired, at least one other person already working there - someone with a family, a routine, a home - got to keep their job. I have a relatively low cost of living, without dependents and with renting my apartment my main expense. I was in the job market on purpose - not because I had been laid off and thrown into the raging depths of unemployment by some misfortune, but by my own volition had jumped ship in search of some more meaningful, ethical work. Even in setback, I have luck and privilege above many of my peers, and will continue to live in solidarity with those struggling most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;ll continue my own job search immediately, with fervor, because I know that&amp;rsquo;s what you all would do in my shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the drawing board.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewing for Software Developer Positions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/interviewing-for-software-developer-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 18:24:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/interviewing-for-software-developer-positions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-search&#34;&gt;The Search&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding a job in the software development field can be daunting even to seasoned candidates. From automated recruiter spam to anxiety-inducing &amp;ldquo;coding challenges&amp;rdquo;, the stress of trying to prove yourself to strangers often stops qualified developers from even applying. We know the methods used to verify a person&amp;rsquo;s competence are misguided and discriminatory (link), yet software companies continue to prop up a cottage industry of test-taking shops in search for the fabled 10x engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Environment #1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 20:25:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello. Lately I’ve been trying to shape myself into a craftsman who works in a few different mediums at least a few times per week. I find that writing about my desires for technical growth keeps my honest about progression. Purposeful declaration of intent is the first step to reaching beyond yourself, right? I’ll explain how I work, how I &lt;em&gt;wish&lt;/em&gt; I worked, and share the single nugget of wisdom I mined this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android Development:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Macbook Pro 2012 15” i7 16GB RAM + SSD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dual monitors (1 1440p wide &amp;amp; 1 1080 vertical) on free swinging arm mounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android Studio (Stable Channel)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Pixel 3XL &amp;amp; Samsung Galaxy S8+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ikea auto-standing desk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since full-fleged application development demands frequent context-switching and multiple concurrent views for code, configuration, layout, build, debug, etc, I’m constrained to a “real computer”. I use MacOS, despite the fact that many of its features are vestiges of a dying metaphor for computational productivity - I’ve had this machine for 7 years and it is sort of like an old truck in terms of reliability and power; it’ll be there to help you move even if it lacks the torque of newer models. I try to only use this thing in “clamshell” mode, docked to my very adhoc workstation monitors. I’ve been thinking of converting to the linux-on-a-mac religion and installing debian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systems Engineering / DevOps Exploration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi 3B+ NAS w/ old laptop HDDs &amp;amp; 3D printed rack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi Zero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad Pro w/ smart keyboard &amp;amp; Termius&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any lazy learner, I owned a raspberry pi for far too long before I did anything even remotely productive with it. Eventually I decided that since I aspire to be a better caretaker of code, I could start by learning how to take care of the machines through which we interface. While I’ve installed PiHole on one to black-hole advertisements in my apartment, I use the other as a playground for lite web design + development, python for little API widgets (YouTube, Twitter), and a NextCloud server connected to my old laptop harddrives so I can replace cloud backup services. Overall, I’ve learned so much more than the ~$40 I spent on these things - so cool because I’m not afraid to break them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgive me Stallman, for I have sinned in the form of an iPad - I had been yearning for a lighter machine that could be powerful enough to do code and writing tasks but simple enough to let me lead the experience and not be drawn in by the dreaded “tweaks” syndrome which affects me on big machines. I hate windows. It is bad, it is a bad operating system by performance and ergonomics standpoints, looks like robots designed it, and now habitually pesters you about Bing in the same place where you receive critical email and chat notifications. At this point I’d expect they’re at least trying to find some way to put ads in the firmware. I couldn’t find a Linux tablet or cheap laptop that seemed both reliable and carefully thought out from a user experience perspective, and the recent spinoff of iOS into iPadOS piqued my interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I bought it. I took it home, had a lot of fun with it right away as the screen is &lt;em&gt;saucy&lt;/em&gt; and GarageBand is pre-installed. Then I started to get to work, jailbreaking it and testing the viability of Cydia apps on the iPad in 2019. Spoiler: It’s not. It’s not even called Cydia anymore. I miss you, Saurik. You are the Obi Wan Kenobi to Geohot’s Anakin Skywalker. I remembered that someone on reddit touted a mere &lt;em&gt;App Store&lt;/em&gt; app as possibly the best terminal experience on iOS, and went to Google it - no, DuckDuckGo it - duck it? Well, it turns out, Termius is amazing and does exactly what I need it to do. Save SSH profiles and give me a terminal with a useful touch interface. Now I can find a song on shuffle at work, remote in to my persistent backup, and youtube-dl it into my personal library. Streaming is great for discovery, but I don’t think I should make it my primary listening experience. Anyway, yeah, it’s great. Now if only we could get Android Studio on this thing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux (Low Level Learning):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$5 Digital Ocean Droplet (Debian) hosting a webserver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friend’s secondhand server equipment (Debian)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purism Librem 5 (an upcoming mobile phone based on Debian and endorsed by the Free Software Foundation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the digitalocean box to host websites, mostly. Angular is cool, I built a small website and then replaced it with a Ghost blog - but will soon reattach the Angular homepage. I got the chance to poke at some retired server equipment with a friend which quickly led to us hosting a Minecraft server - it always leads to this - on which I spent too much time on and then not enough time on - this also always happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a very late student of the Free Software movement - I only stumbled in because I believe in sharing. I now understand how the free software ideology was co-opted by corporations into the term “open source” and purged of all radical socialism. I find his thoughts on power (political not electrical) quite compelling. I summarize my readings of Stallman technopolitics as thus: As someone with some power, I should help others get their fair share of power, because I stand on the shoulders of giants. His views on software development are commendable. Ironically, he seems to believe in freedom in quite a strict sense and is often combative in the interview clips I could find. By tapping into the free software webiverse, I came across the social purpose company Purism which has been working to produce a pure Linux phone with hardware killswitches and voted with my dollars against the surveillance capitalism duopoly. I really hope this thing ships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it. That’s what I do. I wish I was a 10x developer and was pro at every task and tool listed above - I wish I could stop having to hit the arrow keys vim - like forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my nugget of the week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If communication structure determines system design, there is a third phase in which those systems influence the users upon whom its design is impressed. So, naturally, obviously, if we build a system by authoritatively controlling the flow of information among involved parties rather than freely allowing each member to read, understand, and extend the system as a whole, we will encourage our users to think it is okay to trust authoritarian figures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

